Guide to the Robert A. Caro Archive [DATE]–2021 MS 3203
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York (published 1974), [1966–1973?]
  - Subseries III.A. Power Broker research files [cabinet drawer 1], 1907-1972
    - MOSES INTERVIEWS [photocopies], 1967–1968 (Box P1, Folder 2)
      • Robert Moses VII (4/27/68)
    - INTERVIEWS: ARCHS [architects], undated (Box P1, Folder 2)
      • Mrs. Lidia Nelson
      • Richard Guthridge
      • James A. Dawson
      • Isaiah Ehrlich
      • Harry Gould
      • Richard Korchien
      • Simon Brines (partner of Ralph Pommerance)
      • David Levine
      • George Levy
      • Irving Levine
      • Janet Patt
      • Janet Patt II
      • Joshua Lowenfish
      • Bernie Rosen
      • Allen Saalberg
      • Carl Schilling
      • Clarence Stein
      • Henry Wright
      • Michael Zimmer
    - INTERVIEWS: Consol, 1951, 1967–1969 (Box P1, Folder 3)
      • William S. Chapin (4/24/68)
      • John A. Coleman (3/4/67)
      • Jerry Finkelstein (5/1/68)
      • Monroe Goldwater (12/20/67)
      • Mrs. Rudolph A. Halley (4/26/68)
      • Mrs. Elmer B. Howell (4/15/67)
      • Vincent R. Impellitteri (4/22/68)
      • Saul Kaplan
      • Condello
      • Local Laws of the City of New York for the Year 1963, No. 51, A local law to amend the administrative code in the city of New York... [off-track betting on horse races]
      • Judge Jacob Lutsky (5/8/68)
      • Gen. Harry L. Meyers (9/25/68)
      • Charles Michalski (4/25/68)
      • Mrs. Harold Morse (2/21/67?)
      • Richard Childs
      • Mrs. Harold Morse II (8/11/67)
      • Warren Moscow II (12/3/67)
      • Paul O'Dwyer (12/26/67)
      • Lawrence M. Orton (4/21/67)
      • Richard Hooper Pough (4/20/67)
      • Mary Reed (8/6/68)
      • Mrs. Irene Schriber
      • Lloyd B. Reid (6/16/51)
      • Mrs. Florence Shientag [Shoentag?] (5/4/67)
      • Philip Shumsky (11/5/68)
      • Mrs. Mary Smisek (4/7/67)
      • Judge Edward Weinfeld
      • Samuel M. White (11/9/67)
      • Arthur B. Williams Sr. (10/3/67)
      • Arnold and Rebecca La Monte Vollmer (7/6/68)
      • Jim Truex (7/21/68)
      • [Shapiro] (4/17/69)
      • Hazel
      • Weiner
    - INTERVIEWS, 1966–1968 (Box P1, Folder 4)
      • Dolie McWhinney Adams (3/23/67)
      • Samuel Berliner
      • Allbright
      • Robert S. Binkerd (4/4/67)
      • Mrs. Blaine [daughter of Darwin James] (3/29/67)
      • Harold Blake (4/18/68)
      • Peter J. Brennan (7/1/68)
      • Mary Carr (2/16/67)
      • Richard Childs (2/21/67)
      • Arthur E. Buck (5/10/67)
      • Mrs. James B. Cooper Sr. (3/29/67)
      • Colbert
      • James B. Cooper Jr. (3/29/67)
      • Howard S. Cullman (2/7/67)
      • Blake (10/9/67)
      • John E. Cuniffe
      • F. Trubee Davison (5/1/67)
      • Dr. Wilburt Cornell Davison (4/11/67)
      • George Fearon (5/5/67)
      • Mrs. [Lorraine Fishel?]
      • William Floyd-Jones (4/6/67)
      • Kenneth Floyd-Jones
      • Captain Flynn (10/8/66)
      • John M. Gaus (4/14/67)
      • George Gove (2/27/67)
      • Luther Gulick (3/2/67)
      • Len Hall (5/9/67)
      • Horace Havemeyer Jr. (10/13/66)
      • Judge Edgar L. Hazleton
      • Rita Higgins (4/1/67)
      • Robert Livingston Hollins
      • Mrs. Hollins
      • Buell Hollister Jr. / Mrs. William Pedrick
      • Buell Hollister Jr. (2/14/67)
      • Carlos Israels (2/20/67)
    - INTERVIEWS II, 1966–1967 (Box P1, Folder 5)
      • Eugene R. Hurley (9/30/67)
      • John Krumenaker (9/30/67)
      • Bill Latham (11/1/67)
      • Lewis Mayer (6/29/67)
      • Richard Mayes (6/2/67)
      • Raymond Moley
      • William J. Junkamen (12/10/66)
      • Mrs. William Pedrick (2/15/67)
      • Ernest K. Lindley
      • C. H. Maclachlan (5/13/67)
      • Joseph M. Proskauer (2/24/67)
      • Ellwood M. Rabenold (5/15/67) [includes copy of letter from Rabenold to Governor Alfred E. Smith, 5/21/23]
      • Aaron Rabinowitz (2/27/67)
      • Charles Ransom (5/3/67)
      • P. G. Rasweiler (3/24/67)
      • Lloyd Record
      • [Paul?] Reinhardt (5/16/67)
      • Miss Remsen (4/4/67)
      • Lindsay Rogers (2/20/67)
      • James J. Roth (9/28/67)
      • Helen Roth
      • Photostat of deed between Hillary Corwin and Plainview Gardens, Inc. (3/20/37)
      • Townsend Scudder Jr. (3/16/67)
      • Miss Minnie C. Thomas (9/28/67)
      • Joseph P. Warta (4/7/67)
      • Jane Warren
      • William F. Wolter (4/25/67)
      • Ed Skelley (4/11/67)
      • Albert L. Warner (5/9/67)
      • Henry Rogers Winthrop
      • George L. Weeks Jr.
      • Mrs. John A. (Emily Smith) Warner (3/25/67)
    - INTERVIEWS, 1967–1968 (Box P1, Folder 5)
      • L. E. Meador (6/15/67)
      • Chester E. Rightor (7/10/67)
      • Arch Mandel (7/10/67)
      • Philip H. Cornick (7/17/67)
      • Malcolm T. Dougherty (7/20/67)
      • Jackson Dykman
      • E. C. M. Richards (8/21/67)
      • George Gordon Hyde (8/22/67)
      • Morris L. Ernst (11/7/67)
      • Dahlberg
      • Charlton Chute (7/10/67)
      • Lewis [Louis?] Lubin
      • Mrs. Ann Lubin (7/19/67)
      • (Jan) Ruth Larned
      • Louis [Lewis?] Lubin (7/19/67)
      • Edward F. Andrews (7/19/67)
      • Charlie Beavers (7/10/67)
      • Mrs. Paul Sperry
      • Lewis [Louis?] Lubin (7/13/67)
      • Edward O. Proctor (7/23/67)
      • H. Elliot Kaplan (7/7/67)
      • George Friedlander (8/8/67)
      • Mrs. H. E. Heliman (1/23/68)
      • Ralph Clark
      • C. Campbell (7/31/67)
      • Jeremiah Milbank (7/21/67)
      • William R. Babcock (8/14/67)
      • George Gordon Hyde [letter to Caro, 4/8/68]
      • Israel Ben Scheiber (7/13/67)
      • E. A. Johnson (7/22/67)
    - INTERVIEWS: KERN, 1968 (Box P1, Folder 6)
      Paul J. Kern (1/19/68)
      Includes copies of memos and correspondence between Moses and LaGuardia (1934-1935, 1938-1939); and a copy of S. Burton Heath's article "Investigation by Innudendo" from Survey Graphic: Magazine of Social Interpretation, vol. 30, no. 10 (October 1941).
    - INTERVIEWS: LAG [Mayor Fiorello H. La Guardia], 1967–1968 (Box P1, Folder 6)
      • [Berle?]
      • Walter D. Binger (12/22/67)
      • William C. Chanler (12/14/67)
      • Ernie Clark I (5/10/68)
      • Gilmore Clarke (4/55/67)
      • Robert M. Davidson
      • Exton
      • William McD. Griffen (1/18/68)
      • Jack Madigan I (5/2/68)
      • Letter from William Fellowes Morgan to Mr. Kluger (11/18/67)
      • Joseph D. McGoldrick (5/2/67)
      • Jack Madigan I (5/2/68) [photocopy of above]
      • John Mulcahy and Charles Stark (11/6/67)
      • P. Fearson Shortbridge (1/16/68)
      • Olé Singstad (1/10/68)
      • Rexford Guy Tugwell (1/16/68)
      • drawing on envelope
      • Robert C. Weinberg (5/2/68)
      • Paul Windels (11/8/67)
      • Iphigene Ochs Sulzberger (12/11/67)
    - LAZARUS, 1966–1967 (Box P1, Folder 7)
      Reuben Lazarus (2/6/67)
      + correspondence, notes, etc.
    - PAUL MOSES INTERVIEWS, 1966–1967 (Box P1, Folder 7)
      • Paul Moses III (2/10/67)
      • Paul Moses IV (2/9/67)
      • Paul Moses V (3/16/67)
      • Paul Moses [II] (1/16/67)
      • Paul Moses [I] (12/31/66)
      • Paul Moses VI (3/29/67)
    - PAUL MOSES, 1967–1972 (Box P1, Folder 7)
      Clippings, correspondence, notes, research.
    - PAUL MOSES: LEGAL DOCS, [1930–1941] (Box P1, Folder 7)
      Transcripts and copies of obituaries, wills, estate papers, etc., relating to Bella Moses.
    - MOSES' FAMILY, 1934, 1966–1967 (Box P1, Folder 8)
      • Mrs. Emily Sims Marconnier (5/31/67)
      • Jane Moses Collins
      • Monroe Goldwater / Bill Latham / General Harry L. Meyers / Joan Cooney / Nettie Greenberg / Mrs. Elmer B. Howell / Sam White / Mrs. Shientag / Mrs. Morse / Joe Ingraham / Kaltenborn
      • deteriorated newspaper profile (with engraved portrait) of "Mrs." Moses
      • additional clippings, notes, etc.
    - JANE MOSES, 1966–1967 (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Clippings, interview notes, etc.
    - M PERSONAL: SHAPIRO NOTES, [1961–1963, 1970] (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Copies of Moses correspondence and remarks "on the occasion of the award of the Leonard L. Huttleston Executive Award to Sidney Shapiro at the State Council of Parks Annual Meeting," with an 8x10 photograph of Moses presenting award to Shapiro at the May 18, 1970 event.
    - MOSES PERSONAL, 1970–1971, undated (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Clippings, notes, etc.
    - M AT YALE: PHONE NOS., 1967 (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Includes list of names and current [1967] addresses of Yale University Class of 1909.
    - SHAPIRO LETTERS, 1952–1970 (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Correspondence (memos and letters, some originals) from Moses to Sidney M. Shapiro, Chief Engineer and General Manager, Long Island State Park Commission.
    - M AT YALE: COURANT, 1907-1909 (Box P1, Folder 8)
      Copies of Robert Moses's contributions to the Yale Courant, with typed notes by Caro.
    - RM AT YALE, 1909-1966 (Box P1, Folder 9)
      Mostly photocopies, with some typed notes / transcripts by Caro. Includes two pamphlets: Loomis Havemeyer, "My Student Days on Wall Street" (1963) and Ralph H. Clark, "Four Year's Journey with Yale 1909" (1966).
    - 1909–11 RM AT OXFORD, 1967 (Box P1, Folder 9)
      Clippings and letters to a Sandra G. Turner of London regarding Moses.
    - 1915—BMR CON-CON [New York Bureau of Municipal Research], undated (Box P1, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of a New York State Assembly document.
    - BMR [New York Bureau of Municipal Research], 1917, undated (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1914—MCPL C.S. COM [Municipal Civil Service Commission], 1914-1921 (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1916—CLEVELAND (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1916—NYT (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1917—Hog Island (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1917—NYT (Box P1, Folder 10)
    - 1918—NYT (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1919—NYT (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1919—FED'L RECLASS, 1919, 1967 (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1919—RECON COMMISH [Reconstruction Commission of the State of New York] (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1920—NYT (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1920—RECON COMMIS. & 1921—NYSA [Reconstruction Commission of the State of New York / New York State Association], 1920-1921 (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - OLD LONG ISLAND, 1932-1967 (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1922—HT clips (HT notes w/1924) & Bklyn Eagle, 1922, 1924 (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - 1924—TIMES & TRIB COM. (Box P1, Folder 11)
    - [interview notes found between folders], 1968 (Box P1, Folder 11)
      • J. Burch McMorran (4/29/1968)
      • Bertram D. Tallamy (5/14/1968)
    - 1923—Sands Point & Princess Bay Light House (Box P1, Folder 12)
    - PRES-S CHRONOLOGY, 1938, 1967 (Box P1, Folder 12)
      Includes a pamphlet, 40 Years of the House on Madison Street (a circa 1938 history of Madison House, a settlement house at 226 Madison Street, Manhattan), and certification of Robert Moses' birth issued by the Connecticut State Department of Health.
    - Frances Perkins—OHR [Oral History Reminiscences], undated (Box P1, Folder 12)
    - MOSES & SMITH, 1955 (Box P1, Folder 12)
    - SMITH: OHR [Oral History Reminiscences], undated (Box P1, Folder 12)
      Reminiscences of
      • Dr. William H. Allen
      • C. C. Burlingham
      • Mrs. Genevieve B. Earle (1883- )
      • _____ Garagan
      • John H. Lathrop
      • John Lord O'Brien
      • Judge Ferdinand Pecora
      • Lewis H. Pink
      • Lawson Purdy
      • Sen. Martin Saxe
      • Wm. Jay Schieffelin (1866- )
      • Frederick C. Tanner
      • Laurence Arnold Tanzer
      • Norman Thomas
      • George S. Van Schaick
      • Leonard M. Wallstein (1884- )
    - 1924—AL SMITH PAPERS (Box P1, Folder 12)
    - 1923—AL SMITH PAPERS (Box P1, Folder 12)
    - AS & HPS MINUTES, 1921-1927 (Box P1, Folder 13)
    - AS & HP SOCIETY, 1925-1930 (Box P1, Folder 13)
    - BELMONT LAKE, 1941 (Box P1, Folder 13)
    - NSP [Northern State Parkway], 1925-1929 (Box P1, Folder 13)
    - JONES BEACH SCANDAL, 1926-1932 (Box P2, Folder 1)
    - MACY PERSONAL, 1927-1951 (Box P2, Folder 1)
    - MACY-HAVEMYER CORRES. RE PACHOGUE [Pauchogue Land Corporation?], 1924-1929, 1966 (Box P2, Folder 1)
      Originals and contemporary copies, with transcriptions.
    - 1925—AL SMITH PAPERS, 1925-1926 (Box P2, Folder 1)
    - MACY & MOSES, 1932-1959 (Box P2, Folder 2)
    - VUNCK & HER [STUFF?] [Gladys Vunck], 1925-1966 (Box P2, Folder 2)
      Includes folded, hand-colored map of J. D. Macy property bordering Hecksher State Park and Hecksher State Parkway, 1946.
    - HECKSCHER-MACY ORIGS, 1924-1926 (Box P2, Folder 2)
    - MACY—M PATRONAGE & OTHER FAVORS, 1939-1949 (Box P2, Folder 2)
    - 1925—TIMES CLIPS II (Box P2, Folder 3)
    - 1925—TIMES, HT NOTES; HT CLIPS; Lay [Lag?], Pamphlet, RPA (Box P2, Folder 3)
    - 1925—TIMES CLIPS I (Box P2, Folder 3)
    - 1926—TIMES & TRIB NOTES (" [TRIB?] clips) (Box P2, Folder 3)
    - [19]26—STATE REORG. [State Reorganization Commission] (Box P2, Folder 4)
    - BABYLON: THE LEADER, 1910-1928 (Box P2, Folder 4)
      Includes original newspaper clippings from the Babylon Leader, 1927-1928.
    - JONES BEACH, 1930-1969 (Box P2, Folder 4)
    - 1927—BABYLON BEACH, 1927-1929 (Box P2, Folder 4)
    - 1927—BROOKLYN EAGLE (Box P2, Folder 4)
      Includes original newspaper clippings from the Brooklyn Eagle, 1927.
    - 1926—AL SMITH PAPERS (Box P2, Folder 4)
    - NIAGARA—'26, 1924-1933 (Box P2, Folder 5)
    - 1926—BROOKLYN EAGLE (Box P2, Folder 5)
    - 1927—TIMES, HT COMPLETE (Box P2, Folder 5)
      Includes printed Report of the Suffolk County Taxpayers' Association Upon the Improved State and County Highway System of Suffolk County and Trunk Line Highway Arteries Through Queens, Nassau and Suffolk Counties (1927).
    - '27—THOSE 2 SPEECHES, 1927 (Box P2, Folder 5)
      Typescripts of two speeches:
      • "Speech delivered by Hon. Robert Moses, Secretary of State, Chairman of New York State Park Commission, President of Long Island State Park Commission, before the convention of the easter Long Island Real Estate Board, Canoe Place Inn, Hampton Bays, Thursday, June 16, 1927."
      • "Speech delivered by the Honorable Robert Moses, Secretary of State, President of the Long Island State Park Commission, at the banquet of the Long Island Real Estate Board, Montauk Manor, Montauk, Long Island, Friday, September 9, 1927."
    - AL SMITH PAPERS (Box P2, Folder 5)
    - 1932—SMITH PRESIDENT (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1928—TIMES, HT NOTES; HT CLIPS (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1928—AL SMITH PAPERS, 1927-1928 (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1928—EAGLE CLIPS (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - [19]28—FDR LETTERS, 1926-1928 (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1929—TIMES, HT NOTES, CLIPS (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1929—EAGLE CLIPS (Box P2, Folder 6)
    - 1930 (& LISPC Report) (Box P2, Folder 7)
      Includes annotated Report of the Long Island State Park Commission for the Year 1930.
    - 1930—EAGLE CLIPS (Box P2, Folder 7)
    - 1930 FWD-SC PKWYS, 1930-1941 (Box P2, Folder 7)
      Includes holograph letter of Robert Moses to W. Kingsland Macy, February 1, 1931.
    - 1931—NYT & HT (Box P2, Folder 7)
    - 31 (FDR PAP)—YS GRADE XING, 1931 (Box P2, Folder 7)
    - 1931—CS REORG. (Box P2, Folder 7)
    - [19]31—FDR Papers. SEAMAN GORE SUIT (Box P2, Folder 7)
    - 1932—SAVAGE INCIDENT (FDR PAPERS) (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - 1932—FORT SCHUYLER (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - 1932—NYT & HT (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - 1934 Messed up clips (Box P2, Folder 8)
      Clippings (original and microfilm printouts) from various newspapers.
    - PARKS, 1915, 1941 (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - FIRE ISLAND PARK, 1930, 1941 (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - FDR—SMITH, 1920-1928 (Box P2, Folder 8)
    - MISCELLANEOUS BOOKS, undated (Box P2, Folder 9)
    - FDR PAPERS: NOTES, 1923-1932 (Box P2, Folder 9)
    - FDR PAPERS, 1929-1933 (Box P2, Folder 9)
      Many documents stuck together.
    - FDR—M PATRONAGE, 1932 (Box P2, Folder 9)
    - GRADE CROSSINGS, 1924-1928 (Box P2, Folder 9)
    - HECKSCHER FIGHT, 1924-1927 (Box P2, Folder 10)
    - JUDGES: Dike Strong [Norman S. Dike, Selah B. Strong], 1950-1953 (Box P2, Folder 10)
    - DAUGHTER, undated (Box P2, Folder 10)
      Typed notes from Emily Smith Warner's The Happy Warrior: A Biography of My Father Alfred E. Smith (1956).
    - McWhinney [Thomas A. McWhinney], 1922, 1933 (Box P2, Folder 10)
    - Cabinet Meetings, 1927 (Box P2, Folder 10)
    - MACY & THE MAYORALTY, 1933 (Box P2, Folder 10)
    - MORGY DIARIES [Morgenthau], 1935-1939 (Box P2, Folder 10)
      Typed notes from the diaries of Henry Morgenthau Jr. (1935, 1939), U.S. Secretary of the Treasury under Franklin D. Roosevelt.
    - NSP II (RPA) [Northern State Parkway; Regional Plan (Administration?)], 1925-1927 (Box P2, Folder 11)
      Includes
      • The Nassau County Committee and State Parks on Long Island (1925)
      • Charles Downing Lay, Nassau County Committee Report No. 3. The Development of Jones Beach, Long Island as a Great Ocean Park (1925)
      • Charles Downing Lay, A Park System for Long Island. A Report to the Nassau County Committee (1925)
    - Al Smith Papers DPW [Department of Public Works], 1927-1928 (Box P2, Folder 11)
    - Smith—Park Supporter, undated (Box P2, Folder 11)
    - FARLEY, undated (Box P2, Folder 11)
    - TACONIC [Taconic State Park Commission], 1929-1952 (Box P2, Folder 11)
    - JULIUS HENRY COHEN, 1946 (Box P2, Folder 12)
      Notes and photocopies from Julius Henry Cohen's They Builded Better Than They Knew (1946).
    - FRANK GRAHAM, 1945 (Box P2, Folder 12)
      Notes and photocopies from Frank Graham's Al Smith, American (1945).
    - HANDLIN, 1958 (Box P2, Folder 12)
      Notes and photocopies from Oscar Handlin's Al Smith and His America (1958).
    - MACY & JUDGES, 1927-1943 (Box P2, Folder 12)
      Contains original correspondence, 1927-1943.
    - MACY—ZONING, 1944 (Box P2, Folder 12)
    - PRINGLE, 1927 (Box P2, Folder 12)
      Notes and photocopies from Henry F. Pringle's Alfred E. Smith: A Critical Study (1927).
  - Subseries III.B. Power Broker research files [cabinet drawer 2], 1927-1971
    Files from drawer 2 of the four-drawer cabinet holding Caro's Power Broker research. The drawer label read: "The Growth of Power (1934–1945)." Contains research and interview notes (handwritten and typed), newspaper clippings from the New York Times, Herald Tribune, Brooklyn Eagle and others (some are photocopies or printouts, but a substantial portion are originals, and many have been transcribed/summarized by Caro), magazine articles, book passages, and other print matter, and some correspondence. The files here are largely subject oriented, e.g., "Central Park," "East River Drive," etc. Note the folder "My Trips to Parks," which contains Caro's descriptive notes on visits to the Moses-created Heckscher State Park, Hempstead Lake State Park, Jones Beach, and West Hempstead Lake Park on Long Island.
    The files are presented in their original order. Caro's letter-size folders—some of which carry notes on their covers or interiors—have been maintained and grouped inside archival, legal-size folders. Caro's folder titles are keyed to these numbered archival folders. Titles have been transcribed as near to how Caro wrote them as possible, following his capitalization and underlining; any clarifications by the archivist, such as expansions of abbreviations or acronyms, follow in square brackets, e.g., "MID-MAN XWY: LAG [Mid-Manhattan Expressway: La Guardia]."
    - [Filing cabinet label, drawer 2] (Box P3, Folder 1)
      THE GROWTH OF POWER (1934-1945)
    - COMMUNISM!, undated (Box P3, Folder 1)
    - BKS: "GREATER CITY", 1948 (Box P3, Folder 1)
      Notes from Allan Nevins and John A. Kraut, The Greater City: New York, 1898-1948 (1948).
    - BOOKS: MISCELLANEOUS, undated (Box P3, Folder 1)
    - BKS: NEWBOLD, 1955 (Box P3, Folder 1)
      Notes from Newbold Morris, Let the Chips Fall: My Battles Against Corruption (1955).
    - LAG-OHR [La Guardia: Oral History Reminiscences], undated (Box P3, Folder 1)
      OHR: Paul Windels
      OHR: Mrs. Marie La Guardia
    - McAneny (inc. OHR) [Oral History Reminiscence], 1949-1953 (Box P3, Folder 1)
      George McAneny = Manhattan Borough President.
    - MAGS: LAG ERA, 1936-1938 (Box P3, Folder 1)
      Magazine articles from the La Guardia era:
      • Robert Moses, "Municipal Recreation," reprinted from American Architect and Architecture (November 1936)
      • "Pattern for Parks," reprinted from The Architectural Forum (December 1936)
      • "Robert (Or-I'll-Resign) Moses," reprinted from Fortune (June 1938)
      • Robert Moses, "The Changing City," reprinted from The Architectural Forum (March 1940)
      • Hubert Herring, "Robert Moses and His Parks, Harper's Monthly Magazine (undated)
    - Pres. Speech making 1936 (Box P3, Folder 2)
    - 1933—Belle's Funeral (Box P3, Folder 2)
    - 1933—NYT and HT (Box P3, Folder 2)
      Includes original and transcribed newspaper clippings.
    - 1933—NYT & HT CLIPS (Box P3, Folder 2)
      Original newspaper clippings.
    - '33—MAYORALTY, 1933 (Box P3, Folder 2)
      Includes original newspaper clippings.
    - 1934—NYT & HT NOTES (Box P3, Folder 2)
    - 1934—LAG TAKEOVER, 1966 (Box P3, Folder 3)
      Arthur Mann, "When La Guardia Took Over," The New York Times Magazine, January 2, 1966.
    - '34—THE GREAT DRIVE, 1934-1936 (Box P3, Folder 3)
    - '34—NORTH SHORE ALMANAC, 1934 (Box P3, Folder 3)
    - 1935—NYT & HT (Box P3, Folder 3)
      Includes original, deteriorated, newspaper clippings.
    - 1935—PARKS (Box P3, Folder 4)
    - 1935—TBA CONTROVERSY [Triborough Bridge Authority], 1934-1936 (Box P3, Folder 4)
    - 1936—TRIBORO BRIDGE, 1935-1938 (Box P3, Folder 4)
    - '36—ASTORIA FERRY, 1936 (Box P3, Folder 4)
    - MID-MAN XWY: LAG [Mid-Manhattan Expressway: La Guardia], 1936-1940 (Box P3, Folder 4)
    - '36—NYT & HT, 1936 (Box P3, Folder 5)
    - 1936—PARKS (Box P3, Folder 5)
    - CPC [City Planning Commission], 1933-1940, 1970 (Box P3, Folder 6)
    - JAMAICA BAY, 1938-1971 (Box P3, Folder 6)
      Includes original newspaper clippings, and a printed booklet, The Future of Jamaica Bay, issued by the Department of Parks, City of New York (1938).
    - '37—PARKS, 1937 (Box P3, Folder 6)
    - '37—NYT & HT, 1937 (Box P3, Folder 7)
    - '37—PLAYGD CLOSING, 1937 (Box P3, Folder 7)
    - '38—PARKS, 1938 (Box P3, Folder 7)
    - '39—PARKS, 1939 (Box P3, Folder 7)
    - LA GUARDIA, 1936-1938 (Box P3, Folder 7)
    - '38—NYT & HT, 1938 (Box P3, Folder 8)
      Includes many original, deteriorated, newspaper clippings
    - '38—CONSOLIDATION, 1938 (Box P3, Folder 8)
    - '38—WT SERIES, 1938 (Box P3, Folder 8)
      Series of original newspaper clippings for Floyd Taylor's series on Robert Moses, "Danger! Man at Work," from the New York World-Telegram, January 3-8, 1938.
    - 1939—TBTA CONTROVERSY (Box P3, Folder 8)
    - '39—NYT & HT NOTES, 1939 (Box P3, Folder 9)
    - '40—NYT & HT, 1940 (Box P3, Folder 9)
      Includes original, deteriorating, newspaper clippings.
    - '39—NYT & HT CLIPS, 1939 (Box P3, Folder 9)
    - '40—PARKS, 1940 (Box P3, Folder 9)
    - '41—NYT & HT, 1941 (Box P3, Folder 10)
    - '42—NYT & HT, 1942 (Box P3, Folder 10)
    - '41—PARKS, 1941 (Box P3, Folder 10)
    - '42—PARKS, 1942 (Box P3, Folder 10)
    - '43—NYT & HT, 1943 (Box P3, Folder 10)
    - '44—NYT & HT, 1944 (Box P3, Folder 11)
    - '45—PARKS, 1945 (Box P3, Folder 11)
    - 1945—SC WATER [Suffolk County water] (Box P3, Folder 11)
    - '45 FWD—CAPTREE, 1945 (Box P3, Folder 11)
      Captree = Captree Causeway, now Robert Moses Causeway.
    - BBT: LOWER MAN. HISTORY [Brooklyn-Battery Tunnel: Lower Manhattan history], 1971, undated (Box P3, Folder 11)
    - AQUARIUM: DURING WAR, 1941-1948 (Box P3, Folder 11)
      Includes printed booklet, Battery Park: Proposed Reconstruction, issued by the Department of Parks, City of New York (1942).
    - AQUARIUM: AFTER WAR, 1946-1952 (Box P3, Folder 12)